XIAOYU A. GAO

6812 Dean Drive, McLean VA, 22101 | (703) 901-0568 | gao_xiaoyu@bah.com | iknowhtml.github.io | github.com/iknowhtml

Profile

I am a Full Stack Javascript Developer with a passion for technology and innovation. My experience and expertise ranges from designing and implementing responsive and user-friendly UX/UIs to architecting and developing modular, scalable and fault-tolerant back end infrastructures and devops pipelines using Agile development methodologies. In particular, I specialize in technologies such as React/Redux, Node.js/Express, Webpack, Docker, Terraform, Jenkins and AWS.

Education

The University of Virginia: School of Engineering and Applied Science (SEAS)

August 2016

- Computer Engineering & Electrical Engineering
- Rodman Scholar (Honors Program for Top 5% of Engineers)

Skills

Languages:

• JavaScript (ES5/ES6/ES7), Shell (Bash), Java, C/C++

UX/UI and Front End Web Technologies and Tools:

 Sketch, HTML5, CSS3/CSS4, React, Redux, CSS Modules, PostCSS, Webpack

Devops Tools:

• Travis, CircleCI, Jenkins, Terraform, Packer

Development and Testing Tools:

• Agile (Scrum), Git, Mocha, Chai, Babel, ESLint, NPM, Yarn

Back End Web and Database Technologies:

 Node.js, Socket.io, Express, Redis, MySQL, PostgresSQL, MongoDB

Infrastructure Technologies and Cloud Services:

Docker, AWS, Azure, Digital Ocean

Work Experience

Booz Allen Hamilton - Technologist

May 2017 - Present

U.S. Treasury Proof of Concept Blockchain Application - July 2017 - August 2017

- Developed a proof of concept Blockchain application for the U.S. Treasury to replace existing payment infrastructure.
- Front end built with React, Redux, React Router, Redux Form and styled with Spectre.css and custom CSS as a static SPA.
- Back end written in Node, js, and data is persisted on Azure CosmoDB as a MongoDB Database, as well as on the Microsoft's private Ethereum Blockchain.
- Smart contracts written in Solidity with Truffle and deployed to Microsoft's Blockchain network.
- Infrastructure provisioned with Terraform, and front end and back end build and deployment automated with Jenkins.
- SPA and API deployed on Azure Blob Storage and Web Apps respectively, and Geth nodes hosted on Microsoft's Blockchain as a Service.
- Front end files stored in Blob storage proxied with Azure Function App Service to allow accessing static files as website URL.
- Architected the front end, back end and deployment pipeline, as well as the cloud infrastructure for the project.
- Led development efforts across the stack, including the UX/UI design, front end, back end and devops, in a small team of developers in an Agile environment using Kanban.
- Acted as defacto Product Owner and Scrum Master to translate requirements from the stakeholder, and to convert requirements into tasks to be distributed among team members.

FDA Health Blockchain Platform Investment - September 2017 - November 2017

- Architected and bootstrapped the front end for the FDA Health Blockchain Platform Investment.
- Front end logic built with React, Redux, React Router, Redux Form, and user interface styled with custom CSS4 using CSS modules and PostCSS.
- Application transpiled using Babel with a custom written Webpack configuration.
- Led front end development efforts, including designing the UX/UI, implementing application logic, and providing high level guidance to other developers.

Capital One - Technology Development Intern

June 2015 - August 2015

- Developed a sprint tracking web application that aggregates data from various tools such as VersionOne, Git/SVN, Hudson/Jenkin and SonarCubed in an user-friendly and responsive dashboard interface.
- Aided in the design of the UX/UI and implemented front-end logic to display data to users as well as validate inputs using AngularJS, Jquery, SASS and custom CSS.
- Developed RESTful APIs to allow communication between front-end and back-end using Spring Core.
- Deployed application to an internally accessible AWS server.